Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records, 1918-1974 (PPFA I)
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records
1918-1974 (PPFA I)
Planned Parenthood Federation of America
MS 371
106 boxes (41.75 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
The records of the Planned Parenthood Federation of America provide substantial information about the history of the birth control and family planning movement nationally and internationally. The records contain correspondence, memos, minutes, reports, publicity, publications, and congressional and legal materials. They document many aspects of the work of the PPFA and its predecessor organizations, advocacy, medical work, and the activities of its staff and affiliates. The PPFA Records are divided into two portions, PPFA I and PPFA II, this being part I. PPFA I consists of the earlier records of the Federation (1918-74) and is completely organized and open to research. PPFA II consists of records received since 1988, dating from the 1920s to the present, so there is some overlap in dates. PPFA II records are unprocessed and partially restricted.
Historical Note
In 1921 Margaret Sanger founded the national lobbying organization, American Birth Control League (ABCL) which in 1942 became Planned Parenthood Federation of America (PPFA). Between 1921 and 1942 the organization had two transformations. In 1923 Sanger opened the Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau (BCCRB) for the purposes of dispensing contraceptives under the supervision of licensed physicians and studying their effectiveness. In 1921 when she founded the American Birth Control League (ABCL) it provided institutional backing for the clinics. The BCCRB merged with the ABCL in 1939 to form the Birth Control Federation of America (BCFA). In 1942 the name of the BCFA was changed to the Planned Parenthood Federation of America.
The name change reflected a redefinition of the organization's goals from family limitation to family planning. While PPFA continued to function as the largest birth control organization in the country, it sought to position itself as a more mainstream and moderate organization committed to a broad range of programs related to reproductive health. Under the leadership of National Director D. Kenneth Rose, the PPFA expanded its programs and services through the 1940s, adding affiliate organizations throughout the country. By the end of World War II, the Federation was no longer solely a center for birth control services or a clearing house for contraceptive information but had emerged as a major national health organization. PPFA's programs included a full range of family planning services including marriage education and counseling, and infertility services. The leadership of the PPFA, largely consisting of businessmen and male physicians, endeavored to incorporate its contraceptive services unofficially into regional and national public health programs by emphasizing less politicized aspects such as child spacing. During the 1950s, the Federation further adjusted its programs and message to appeal to a family-centered, more conservative post war populace, while continuing to function, through its affiliated clinics, as the more reliable source of contraceptives in the country.
From 1942 to 1962, PPFA concentrated its efforts on strengthening its ties to affiliates, expanding public education programs, and improving its medical and research work. By 1960, visitors to PPFA centers across the nation numbered over 300,000 per year.
In the 1950s PPFA began focusing greater attention on global population issues as new concerns arose over the political, social and cultural implications of overpopulation in Asia and around the world. It became active in international birth control work through is membership in the International Planned Parenthood Federation (IPPF), which Margaret Sanger helped found in 1952. In 1961 the population crisis debate, along with funding shortages, convinced PPFA to merge with the World Population Emergency Campaign, a citizens fund-raising organization to become PPFA-World Population. (This history is excerpted from The Margaret Sanger Papers Microfilm Edition: Smith College Collection Series)
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The records of the Planned Parenthood Federation of America date from 1918 to the present and document the work of PPFA and its predecessor organizations, national and international, in the areas of advocacy, medical research, legislative reform, public relations, as well as the work of individual administrators, staff, and affiliated organizations. The collection is a significant source of information on all aspects of the history of birth control and family planning, including women's health issues; sex education; women in poverty; international population planning and policy; and the legal, political and social aspects of contraception and abortion. Types of material include correspondence; memoranda; minutes; reports; financial records; legal records; publicity; publications; photographs; audio tapes; video tapes; and posters.
The records are divided into two portions, PPFA I and PPFA II, this being section I. PPFA I consists of the earlier records of the Federation (1918-74), and is completely organized and open to research. PPFA II consists of records received since 1988, dating from the 1920s to the present, so there is some overlap in the dates. The PPFA II Records are unprocessed, but restricted materials (see information on use) have been segregated from those that are open to research. The container list for PPFA II is not online, but a print version is available in the Sophia Smith Collection.
Organization of the Collection
This collection is organized into seven series:
I. American Birth Control League
II. Birth Control Federation of America
III. Planned Parenthood Federation of America
IV. Planned Parenthood - World Population
V. Related Organizations
VI. Correspondence
VII. Subject Files
Oversize Materials
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The Records of the Planned Parenthood Federation of America (Part I) are open to research. Records in Part II that are dated 1985 and later are closed to research use. Permission may be acquired in writing from PPFA to view restricted records.
Additional Formats
The Records of the Planned Parenthood Federation of America (Part I) are available on microfilm in the Sophia Smith Collection and via interlibrary loan.
History of the Collection
The early accessions to the PPFA records were received from Loraine Campbell, Margaret Sanger, and others in the 1970s. Beginning in 1988, the records have come directly from Planned Parenthood Federation of America.
Search Terms
Best, Winfield; Guttmacher, Alan Frank, 1898-; McCormick, Katherine Dexter, 1876-1967; Rose, D. Kenneth; Sanger, Margaret, 1879-1966; Wattleton, Faye; Alan Guttmacher Institute--History--Sources; American Birth Control League--History--Sources; Abortion--Law and legislation-United States--History--Sources; Abortion services--History--Sources; Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau (New York, N.Y.)--History--Sources; Birth Control Federation of America--History--Sources; International Planned Parenthood Federation--History--Sources; Planned Parenthood Federation of America--History--Sources; Planned Parenthood-World Population (U.S.)--History--Sources; Birth control clinics--United States--History--Sources; Birth control--History--20th century--Sources; Birth control--Developing countries--History--20th century--Sources; Birth control--Law and legislation--United States--History--Sources; Birth control--Research--History--Sources; Contraceptives--Research--Sources; Hygiene, Sexual--History--20th century--Sources; Human reproduction--Political aspects; Population policy--History-20th century--Sources; Reproductive health--Statistics; Sex instruction--History--Sources; Women--Health and hygiene--United States--20th century--Sources; Women's health services--United States--20th century--Sources
Additional Information
Related Material
See also the PPFA II Records. Portions of PPFA Subject series (A-B) are in the Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records, Countway Library, Harvard University. Related material can be found in the Margaret Sanger Papers.
- Series I. AMERICAN BIRTH CONTROL LEAGUE (1918-1942)1921-1939, 2.25 linear ft.
  Annual Meetings, Conferences, General Administration, Literature.
- Series II. BIRTH CONTROL FEDERATION OF AMERICA (1937-1944)1939-1942, 2.25 linear ft.
- Series III. PLANNED PARENTHOOD FEDERATION OF AMERICA1942-1962, 14.25 linear ft.
  (1916-1966) Annual Meetings, Committees, Conferences, General Administration, Law and legislation arranged by state and Congressional Session, Literature, Mailings, Policies and programs arranged by subject including international work arranged by country and state work arranged by state.
- Series IV. PLANNED PARENTHOOD - WORLD POPULATION1961-, .5 linear ft.
  (1961-1969) literature, newsletters, reports, reprints, miscellaneous
- Series V. RELATED ORGANIZATIONS, 2.5 linear ft.
  (1924-1964) Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau, National Committee on Federal Legislation for Birth Control, National Committee on Maternal Health, National Committee for Planned Parenthood, International Planned Parenthood Federation.
- Series VI. CORRESPONDENCE, 7 linear ft.
  (1922-1974) U.S. Government and individual arranged alphabetically.
- Series VII. SUBJECT FILES, 12.75 linear ft.
  (1920-1959) Subjects arranged alphabetically including state contraception laws under Greenbaum, Wolff and Ernst, arranged by state.
- Series I. AMERICAN BIRTH CONTROL LEAGUE (1918-1942)1921-1939
  - Annual Meetings1922-1939
    - 1922-1934 (Box 1, Folder 1-13)
    - 1935 (Chicago) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1935 (New York) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 16-19)
  - Conferences
    - First American Birth Control Conference1921 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Birth Control meetings1924 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - National Birth Control Conference1929 November
      - General (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - "Birth Control and Social Welfare" texts 1929 November 18 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - "Achievements and Plans of Birth Control Organizations" texts 1929 November 19 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        - Proceedings (Box 2, Folder 6)
        - Reports (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - "Birth Control and the Law," luncheon with Mary Ware Dennett (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - "Birth Control and Health" session 1929 November 19 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Mass Meeting proceedings 1929 November 19 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - "Birth Control and Race Improvement" 1929 November 20 (Box 2)
        - Proceedings (Box 2, Folder 11)
        - Texts (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Conference of the New England States on Birth Control 1931 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Conference of the Southern States on Birth Control 1931 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - New York State Conference 1932 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
      - Mass Meeting, "Birth Control and the Social Crisis"1935 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Five State Regional Conference on Birth Control, Baltimore, Maryland1935 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Five State Regional Conference on Birth Control, St. Louis, Missouri1935 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Middle Atlantic Regional Conference, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania1936 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - General Administration
    - Administration1927-1938 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Advisory Council1926-1930 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Aims1921-1937 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - American Eugenics Society: proposed merger with ABCL1933 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports1935-1938 (Box 3, Folder 5-8)
    - Board of Directors1935-1937 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Bylaws1922-1937 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    - Correspondence1921-1938, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12-16)
    - Legislative Work1924-1928 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Massachusetts case: Commonwealth of Massachusetts v. Carolyn T. Gardener, et al1938 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Membership and fundraising appeals1928-1931 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Membership Department1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - National Council of Lay Leaders1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - National Medical Council on Birth Control1937 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Organization and future policy1932-1934 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Outreach: solicitation of support191928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Public Opinion Poll1932 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Publicity, Newspapers, Southern1934-1941 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Reports, Executive Secretary1922-1931 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Staff Reports (Box 4)
      - General1927-1937 (Box 4, Folder 8-13)
      - Executive Director: Analysis of 7309 "Mother's" Letters1933 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Executive Secretary1922-1931 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
    - State Leagues (Box 4)
      - Executive Secretaries' Meeting1940 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Reports for ABCL Annual Meetings1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 18-21)
    - State Organization Report1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Literature
    - 1927-1938 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Catalog, General1935, 1936, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 2-4)
    - Reprints1928-1937 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Birth Control Review (Box 6)
      - Advertising1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Book Reviews1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Consulting Editors1939 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Copyright1933 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - History1918-1939 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Postal Matters1918-1934 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Street Selling1926 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Subscription Appeals1928-1931 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Series II. BIRTH CONTROL FEDERATION OF AMERICA (1937-1944)1939-1942
  - Annual Meeting1940
    - Plans and Preparation 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - January 23 1940 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - January 24 1940 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - January 25 1940 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Press 1940 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Annual Meeting1941
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Clinic Session (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Finance Session (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Invitations (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Luncheon (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Press Releases of Speeches (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Publicity (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Symposium on Population (Box 7, Folder 115)
    - Twentieth-Fifth Anniversary of First Clinic: scrapbook (Box 7, Folder 16-18)
      Scrapbook is disassembled.
  - Annual Meeting1942
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - News Releases (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, Birth Control Federation of America Conference1941 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - General Administration
    - Annual Report1939 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Appropriations Committee1938-1940 (Box 9, Folder 1A)
    - Banning of Planned Parenthood Exhibit from New York State Fair1941 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - By-laws1939-1943 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Division of Negro Service1940 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Finance, Recommendations from State Committees1939-1944 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - History1935-1941 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Interdepartmental Committee to Coordinate Health and Welfare Activities1939 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Meetings1934-1940 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Name Change from ABCL to PPFA1937-1942 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - National Advisory Committee1939-1943 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - National Clinic Service Budget1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Press Releases, Publicity, Clippings1941 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Regional Organization Reports1940 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Structure and Function1937-1938 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Literature
    - General1938-1941 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Medical1937-1941 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Reprints1937-1940 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Literature Catalog1939 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
    - Literature Catalog, General1941 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Literature Catalog, Medical1941 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Journal of Contraception
      - Advertising1938 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Book Review Requests, Publishers1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Change of Name1939 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Copyright1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Exchanges, Magazines1938 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Foreign Clinics1938 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Postal Correspondence1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Postal Regulations1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Printing1937-1939 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Promotion Program1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Questionnaire1936 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Reports1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Schilling Press1938-1940 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Stone, Abraham, Editor1939 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Subscriptions1939-1940 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Suggestions for Growth of the Journal1936-1939 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - First idea and first volume1935 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Series III. PLANNED PARENTHOOD FEDERATION OF AMERICA1942-1962
  - Annual Meeting1943
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Invitations (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Plans/Preparation (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Publicity (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - State Federations (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Annual Meeting1944
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Plans/Preparation (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Annual Meeting1945
    - Luncheon, Dinner (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Plans (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Annual Meeting1946
    - Institute (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Minutes (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Plans (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Publicity (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Radio (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Workshop Session (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Annual Meeting1947
    - Luncheon (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Minutes (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Plans (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - State League Reports (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - State Representatives (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Workshop Session (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Annual Meetings
    - 1948-1952 (Box 14, Folder 8-12)
    - 1959 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - 1966 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Committees
    - Field Committee
      - Agendas, minutes, memos1947-1952 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Executive Staff Advisory Committee1947 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Field Reports1940-1947 (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
    - Long Range Planning Committee
      - Correspondence with Mrs. Mauck1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - MeetingMarch 1, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous1948-1949 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Regional Reports1949 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
    - National Campaign Steering Committee, Minutes, Memos1947-1950 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - National Clergymen's Advisory Committee
      - Budget1945 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Catholic Opposition1946 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Cooperation with Religious Leaders1946 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Efforts in Formation1944 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Executive Committee, Subcommittee on Population1946 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - General1946 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Invitations and Responses1942-1943 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Invitations and Responses1944-1945 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Mailings1942-1944, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
      - MeetingsMarch 1941-October, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 1-10)
      - Memoranda1943-1946 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - "Ministerial Counselling and Planned Parenthood," 1943-1946 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Nominating Committee1945 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Nomination and Final Balloting1943-1944 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Organization Committee1942-1943 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Pamphlet, Syllabus and Correspondence1944-1946 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - Pamphlet Publication Project1946 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Planning Committee1943 (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Publicity1941 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Religious Statement1943 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Report to Executive Committee1944 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Resolutions
        - 1946 (Box 19, Folder 3)
        - Comments1947 (Box 19, Folder 4)
        - Distribution1946 (Box 19, Folder 5)
        - Pending1946 (Box 19, Folder 6)
        - State League1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 7)
        - Suggested1947 (Box 19, Folder 8)
        - Unfavorable1946 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Signers of Statement by Religious Leaders1940-1943 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Statements by 25 Religious Leaders1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Subcommittee Meeting1943 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Suggestions from State League1940-1944 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Syllabus for Dean of Theological Seminaries1943-1945 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - National Medical Advisory Council1946 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Nominating Committee1951-1952 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Program Committee1942-1946 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Public Information Committee1939-1944 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Committee on Public Progress1938-1940 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Social Research Committee1961 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Social Work Advisory Committee
      - Establishment1942-1943 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Invitations to Serve, Acceptances, Refusals, Planning Committee1945 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - MeetingsJanuary - May, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 9-11)
      - Minutes, Correspondence, Memoranda1944 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Minutes, Correspondence1947-1948 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Committee to Study State League and Regional Organization1945-1946 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Digest of Minutes for PPFA Operating Committees1946-1947 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Conferences
    - Mid-West Regional Conferences1942 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Workshop for national and local staffJune 1942 (Box 21, Folder 1a)
    - Town Hall Forum, Planned Parenthood in Wartime1943 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Labor and Planned Parenthood, Conference1947 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Workshop Conferences and Regional Staff Meetings, Schedule1952 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Regional Workshop publicity1954 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - General Administration
    - Board of Directors: Agendas, Minutes, Notes1947-1952 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Board of Directors: Handbook1954 (Box 21, Folder 7-9)
    - Budgets1943-1947 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - By-laws
      - 1942-1961 (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
      - Adaptation to Local Needs1948-1949 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Revision Committee1949-1950 (Box 22, Folder 9-11)
    - Exhibits, 1938-1942 (Box 22, Folder 12-15)
    - Executive Committee and Board of Directors Minutes1947-1951 (Box 23, Folder 1-6)
    - Fundraising1947-1960 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - History1948, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Membership Appeals and Statistics1939-1946 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Newsletters (Box 23)
      - Information Service1942 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - News Exchange1944-1951 (Box 23, Folder 11-18)
      - PPFA News Letter1942 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Press Releases1939-1951 (Box 23, Folder 20-26)
    - Pilot Study on the Growth of American Families1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
    - Statement of Support from OB/GYN Doctors1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Treasurer's Annual Reports1939-1947 (Box 24, Folder 4-7)
    - "'Yardsticks': A report to the Executive Committee of the Planned Parenthood Federation of America from the Federation staff,"1945 September 20 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Law and Legislation
    - Connecticut
      - Amicus Curiae Brief1942 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Amendment to bill1940 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence1939-1957 (Box 24, Folder 11-12)
      - Connecticut Committe to Make Birth Control Legal1940-1941 (Box 24, Folder 13-14)
      - Field Reports regarding legislators1942-1944 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Joint Action with Massachusetts1943-1944 (Box 24, Folder 16-17)
      - Legal Briefs, Decisions (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - Legal Publications, State and Federal1932-1943 (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - News Releases1940-1942 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Publicity1939-1941 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Tileston Case
        - Correspondence1942-43 (Box 25, Folder 3)
        - Reports1942 (Box 25, Folder 4)
        - Supreme Court Decision1942 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Massachusetts
      - Abstracts1939-1942 (Box 26, Folder 1)